<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>function_objects on #anooptube</title>
    <link>https://anooptube.in/tags/function_objects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in function_objects on #anooptube</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 22:06:52 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://anooptube.in/tags/function_objects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Recursion</title>
      <link>https://anooptube.in/blog/post24/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 22:06:52 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anooptube.in/blog/post24/</guid>
      <description>Recursion is a programming concept where a function calls itself during its execution. In C++, recursion allows you to solve complex problems by breaking them down into smaller, simpler versions of the same problem.
To implement recursion in C++, you typically define a function that calls itself until it reaches a base case, which is a condition that terminates the recursive calls.
For Example, in order to print n numbers, the base concept is output the a given number and the condition is to print the number is less than or equal to the given limit say n.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Function Objects</title>
      <link>https://anooptube.in/blog/post23/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 21:48:13 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anooptube.in/blog/post23/</guid>
      <description>In C++, a function can be treated as an object using function pointers or function objects (also known as functors). Function objects are objects that can be invoked like functions.
They provide a way to encapsulate a function within an object, allowing it to be passed around, stored in data structures, or used in algorithms that require callable entities.
A functions can be treated as first-class citizens, meaning they can be assigned to variables, passed as arguments to other functions, and returned from functions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
